[Music]
the following is a production of Frankie
greatest and the internet Museum of
holography
speaking about me they knew they knew
what I ate they know what I drink they
do a movie that I watched where I was
fun they knew what what cigarettes they
used to smoke and and everything they
they did they must have watched
something on the internet I don't know I
knew everything about me knew everything
about me knew everything about me knew
everything about me that's right
standard we're watching you oh yeah yeah
don't you just love the way the internet
is portrayed in the media hello this is
Frankie play this and welcome to another
week of hollow talk this is our special
guest week and we also have our listener
you know and questions to get to so
let's get this week's show on the road
[Music]
thank you
hello and welcome to another week of
Holo talk this is Frankie Freitas your
host I'm here tonight with Debbie Lee
Debbie how are you tonight I'm fine
Frank how are you okay are you getting
ready for the holidays I'm trying
you're not ready yet no I haven't even
started I haven't started anything yet
either I'm one of those people that goes
out Christmas Eve and gets all the
shopping finished on Christmas Eve
that's cutting it close that's cutting
it real close what happens if you don't
find what you want
I always find something you know there's
so much out there how can you not find
something I guess yeah
Our Guest this week is Wang Chun who is
known as hunter from holographic
Development Company Limited in Shenzhen
China Hunter will be giving us an inside
look at the development of holography in
China so we're looking forward to
bringing this interview to our whole
talk listeners our musical guests this
evening
Emi recording artists they've sold over
2 million records worldwide and they've
been recently seen on MTV and just had a
large Newsweek article done on them full
page Newsweek article and we're hoping
with bands such as Junoon to bring Holo
talk listeners a global experience with
music have you heard any of their music
yet no I haven't okay I've heard it and
I
I've become a fan I think they're pretty
good they're from Pakistan and they're a
rock band and they have a very
interesting sound to them a global sound
so we'll be hearing from them we're
currently booked on the show up until
September of 98. I'm not going to go
through the list again we'll go through
that maybe on one of the off weeks we've
added a few more people
if you're someone who's involved with
the field of Photography out there and
you haven't yet heard from myself in
order to be a guest I'll still be in
touch but I know who you are and where
you are and I certainly don't want to
overlook anyone ever it's just that
that we're into our I believe it's the
fourth week now aren't we Brotherhood
yeah yeah and
I certainly did not expect the show to
be booked until September of 98. that
happened quick that happened quick so
we're going to get everyone on the show
okay let's move on and let's go first to
a telephone question that we got this
week from one of our listeners
but I have a question that is I'm doing
a report on holography and so I've been
reading several different books and
articles Etc and one of the things that
came up and having a hard time
understanding is when you I read that if
you cut a hologram in half you would
still have all the information there in
the complete picture there
um
and in just half of the film which is
kind of hard to understand I would
expect that you would just have half the
Hologram or half of the image anyway I
couldn't stand it anymore I had one
hologram and so I went ahead and I cut
it in half and sure enough I only had
half the image which is what I expected
to see but not what I read I would see
so I'm wondering if you could give me a
better explanation of why you should
have the whole image there and also why
I only ended up with half the image when
I cut my hologram in half
well it's very unfortunate that you cut
a hologram up to find that out
um
that works best
when you're using a laser transmission
hologram now this this is something that
goes has been going around for a long
time that if you break a hologram up
into a thousand pieces each one of the
pieces will contain the entire image and
that's true to a point what happens is
let's say you have a laser transmission
hologram normally with a laser
transmission hologram the object is
located much further away from the
holographic film or the holographic
plate then you find with other Holograms
like your reflection Holograms which you
probably have
that you cut up
well if you were to cut a laser
transmission hologram into four pieces
what would happen is if you took the
upper left hand piece
and looked through that you would see
the entire object but you would see the
entire object from that upper left hand
perspective
and so on and so forth with each
now with the reflection hologram they're
usually copied from a laser transmission
master and that object is much closer to
the plane of the holographic Emulsion
itself
so that when you cut that hologram you
don't have enough distance there to look
through that individual piece and see
the perspective of that object from that
piece so while this is true
it's more true with certain Holograms
than others and notably true with the
laser transmission hologram I'm sorry I
had to cut your hologram up to find that
out okay as usual we've received quite a
few emails this week with listeners
questions
we have the guest we're not going to do
all of the email questions we save those
for the weeks in between so we'll take a
few tonight so Deb you have a list of
them there why don't we go to our first
one okay Frank why are some Holograms
green and others gold and other colors
I saw this question come through and
there's really no simple answer to this
there are quite a few different
techniques that are used in holography
that can give you different results as
as far as the final color of the
Hologram itself is concerned
you're probably speaking more of a
reflection Holograms the type that you
see in the holography shops and as you
walk down the aisle or wherever the
Holograms are displayed you see some
Holograms are green some of them are
gold some of them are red and
it all depends on how the Hologram
itself was processed if you're using
silver halide emulsion
um
if you do a hologram and you do a
processing technique where that Emulsion
does not it experience any shrinkage you
will find that that hologram will play
back at the same wavelength or close to
the same wavelength that created it so a
few major hologram using a helium neon
laser operating at 633 nanometers in the
red part of the spectrum if you use a
processing technique which does not
allow that Emulsion to shrink
your hologram will play back very close
to that wavelength and your hologram
will be red
however if you use one of the techniques
that actually removes some of the
material from the Emulsion and that
gelatin layer shrinks you get a shift
away from the red part of the spectrum
and that hologram now plays back at a
shorter wavelength which moves it away
from the red into the gold or the yellow
and that's what happens when you see
some of those goldish type of holograms
now
with the photopolymer Holograms it's a
completely different thing altogether
and what you're getting is a material
that's playing back and very close to
the wavelength of the Argon laser that
used to create the Hologram because your
wavelength working with the photopolymer
Holograms is actually in the green and
blue part of the spectrum
now you can also control
collar in a hologram by using a
technique that's called triethanolamine
and that's getting a little bit too far
into how we need to answer this question
at the point but what I'd just like to
put in here is the fact that you can
control the shrinkage of that Emulsion
by expanding it first before you do the
exposure and this will give you what's
considered color control so if you do a
multiple exposure each one of those
exposures
after that hologram has been processed
can have different colors when a
hologram plays back you have a multiple
color reflection hologram so that's in a
nutshell and the best that I can do
right now as far as why some Holograms
are green why some Holograms are red why
some Holograms are gold
more than likely if it's a silver halide
Emulsion that's being used it's all due
to the individual processing technique
that was used for that hologram
as we promised on one of the other shows
we weren't going to let our listeners
sit through an entire show before our
guest comes on and I'm going to stick to
that promise so what we're going to do
now is move on to the interview with
Hunter
now there's something very special about
this interview that I'd like to tell you
about as I set this up Hunter does not
speak any English
when he decided to be a guest on the
show I sent him a list of questions
and he was actually tutored in English
so he could answer them the interview
ran
probably between 25 and 30 minutes
and what I had to do was take that
interview and go into one of the digital
editing programs and edited apps so that
it sounded really good so the interview
turned out to be just slightly less than
15 minutes after all that was edited out
wow
in any case I hope I did a good job
Hunter if you're listening I hope you'll
be very pleasantly surprised at how you
sound in the interview and it was a
pleasure speaking with you and amazing
that you were sitting somewhere in China
and I was sitting somewhere in a small
town in Pennsylvania talking to you so
let's move on to the hunter interview
I'd also like to invite you
to visit the holographic Development
Company Limited website which has the
link right on the holotalk page so if
you go back there you'll find a link to
that and visit them
the World Wide Web perhaps even as
you're listening to the interview so
let's go on and listen to what Hunter
has to say about holography in China
this is Frankie fighters from holotalk
fine thank you very glad to talk with
you I'm glad you're on the air Hunter
could you tell us a little bit about
your company uh holographic Development
Company Limited my company established
in the middle of this year opened with
my friend and me
actually it's a new company and I think
our major commission is to Market a
display Holograms around China you know
we we have marketing the Holograms
through past half a year and our
business going to succeed yes and I
think we are you know as far as I can
say maybe only company doing this kind
of marketing job for displaying
Holograms in China in China how are
Holograms used in China are they used in
magazines or packaging the Hologram in
China commonly used only for the label
on some small package I see that's
that's what we can see anywhere I think
in U.S and in other countries and it's
also you know like some inbox labels yes
that takes almost 99 in China and
usually they are very small they are
wine to two centimeter squares
I can find some bigger ones in abroad
but in China it's only small ones
actually we never say any other use like
in the magazine cover or books or any
any package in the package they have
some not hologram they have some a shiny
materials like a hologram papers I see
where can you see Holograms do they have
stores that sell Holograms in China if
someone were in China where would you go
a hologram well first of all you owe
through the China there is no hologram
gallery or Museum really and there is no
such a museum or Gallery that's I what I
can say because I have traveled many
cities around China to search for the
Hologram and I have visited many
scientists in China they dedicate their
whole life developing development of
China
but they told me there is no such a
given very small Gallery every time when
they show the Hologram to people you
know it's always something totally new
to most of Chinese I see do you expect
to see that change sometime in the
future that's what we want to contribute
in this situation in China
do you have any Organization for
art
holography in China we don't have a
professional uh holographic artists but
we have some scientists they're doing
research in holography you know usually
create some hard Holograms but not
professional we don't have such an
organization in China and recently as a
company and we want to dedicate in the
art field of hologram in China so we
send many letters to companies and
organizations around China to appeal
such a organization we hope in the next
year
in China we can found such a
organization to develop the art
holography in China do the scientists
ever show
or exhibit the work that they've done
anywhere in China
no no one ever has a chance to see the
work that's being done
no
no I think they only you know show their
Awards in their laboratory and the no
such a x-spacing in China the schools in
China do they teach about holography in
the schools
uh well in the college especially in the
physics department and science
department they have some class on laser
and the holograph hologram but in the
high school and in the other departments
in the universities they don't have the
class to teaching the Hologram a
holographic technique I see and that
because they don't have this kind of
class if you bring some hologram to the
University campus most of students never
see the Hologram and they you know they
don't know what what it makes yeah yeah
is your company involved with any of the
schools in China
teach any of the students about what
it's all about to give them a chance to
see this technology we have you know in
the past two months we have opened six
expenses in high schools and the wine
College
in our city thank Clay City and the
students you know show a great interest
in the Hologram we cooperate with the
education Bureau in this city to make a
project educate on educating holographic
technique around High School in this
city and the next year we will have some
detail project in every class in every
school on the Hologram technique that's
wonderful congratulations oh thanks
about the school I think in every school
we don't have
especially high school we don't have any
holographic equipment and any kind of
hologram
demonstration in the school so the
student never you know can imagine such
a thing
and after they visit our expression the
students write many compositions about
their idea about hologram some of the
completions we have gathered are very
good idea and we want to publish a book
on the student's idea after the
they say the real hologram
so most of the people who are doing
holography in China are scientists
do you have any
people doing Holograms like as a hobby
in China
uh well I don't think so no I don't
think so so what is your company's
recent plan for the next year or so and
what do you see as your
forward-looking plan maybe five ten
years down the road where do you expect
to be at that time one of our recent
plan is the education we focus our
attention on the educational holographic
around the China and the recently maybe
by the I mean if not next year we want
to get hologram education and popular in
some maybe two or three major cities in
China and we're planning to open more
Expressions by the beginning of next
year around this city especially in the
schools yes and the the schools can you
know get attention of the Hologram and
especially the scientific point of view
of hologram to the students and they are
very interesting in this new tech in
China and the reason currently we also
plan to
open
some public
spaces
in our city
besides our city there is there will be
a new uh Science Center and they have a
new showroom the first show will be the
Hologram technique and the the show will
maybe visit by four million people in
four or a half a year and we want to you
know get the hologram
you know through this expression to
local people here New City Shenzhen City
yeah I do not think that most people in
the United States know about Shenzhen
but it's a very modern city isn't it
yeah it's one of the most modern city in
China and it this city is the first
economic free zone in China
this is one one of the four
economic advanced cities in China to
make a worldwide show of our company and
the holographic situation in China is
also one of our recent clients we will
hopefully finish this job by the January
next year
are you close to Hong Kong
yeah it's uh only several miles I see so
anyone who's visiting on vacation Hong
Kong
should definitely go over to Shenzhen
City and see the city itself
you know since uh China you know have
that reform and opening policy and
actually sent them this city is a window
of if they reform and opening policy of
China well maybe someday I'll come over
to Shenzhen City
welcome I'll bring all the equipment
with me
I think everything that we need to make
some Holograms and we'll go around to
some of the schools while I'm there and
we'll make some Holograms with the kids
how's that
well that that's wonderful if you can
come here hologram and the holographic
technique it's uh you know it's not a
single technique or a picture to most of
Chinese New Year they are something you
know really new and something really
fascinating to to them if you if you can
come here by that way you are definitely
welcomed by
the whole Chinese so Henry do you have
any closing remarks that you'd like to
say to the listeners before we sign off
here thank you for offering me and my
company such an opportunity to talk with
you and holograph a fan you know I as a
little child I read as far as I can
remember I read that scientific fiction
book and it's called laser City and you
know in the book it told me many things
about laser about holographic telephone
holographic movie or something easy not
you know invented right now but as a
little child I'm so fancy about hologram
also as saying artist you know I used to
learn art for many years and I hope all
the holographers around the world can
read it in China and show their Works in
China if they are interesting I
I hope they can make lectures and hold
Expressions even create their own Works
in China in any case I will be you know
help them find my best okay thank you
very much Hunter it's been wonderful
speaking with you through this magic
technology of telephones and now
everyone who logs on around the world
will be able to hear you write on their
own computers when they listen to
holotalk this week
so thank you very much for being a guest
okay thank you
okay so that was the hunter interview
Hunter's company is holographic
Development Company Limited in Shenzhen
China
he has a website that we put up for him
for uh his company don't forget to stop
by the link is right on the whole world
page right where you log on to see how
listen to Holo talk so visit the page
and you can actually see some of the
photos from China of Hunter going out
into the field and working with the
children in China to teach them about
lasers and Holograms Etc it's a nice uh
nice little site okay we started our
icon program this week if you'd like to
support Holo talk you can grab one of
the small holotalk images and sit on
your own home page and Link it to the
talk show if you like we're also looking
into the possibility of doing the show
with video as well after the beginning
of the new year if you may remember
seven out of 10 people who responded to
our last survey on the website said that
they would like to watch holotalk along
with listening to it so we're looking
into a few unique ways to use this
technology
okay let's move on let's uh
let's move on to another question
that I talked about medical application
um with holography and my question was
that um I've heard about using Holograms
to detect like
um
the new polygons to show the body and
you can see the um if it's symmetrical
or not and that will determine determine
if you have bone structure that is not
formed correctly or muscular structure
does not formed correctly and I went to
to get more information on that
holography has been used in the medical
fields for many years in fact we should
get Bert Myers on the show who's been
working with medical imaging holographic
Imaging for quite a few years down at
the Veterans Administration Hospital
down in New Orleans
um
the types of holograms that I've seen
that showed effects on the body were
basically a holographic interferograms
or interferometry where you could see
the effect that different things had on
the body such as vibration I saw a
series of holograms that were made of
people who were tested using power tools
and the effect that the vibration has on
the person's body using these tools such
as a jackhammer other Holograms that
I've seen in the medical field have been
where you've had implants such as ball
joints into sockets and you could see
how the implant had a stress effect on
the actual bone that it was connected to
and once again this was done through
holographic interferometry so there's a
lot of applications using holography in
the medical field there's company which
is called voxel I think voxel which
manufactures an Imaging device where
Holograms can be made of CAT scans and
things of that nature and you can view
the holographic cat scan as if you were
viewing almost like an x-ray but you're
seeing a completely three-dimensional
view of that scan so let's hold off on
that that's that's all I'm going to give
you for now and let's see if we can't
get someone like Bert Myers on the show
we could do a special show for a medical
holography itself
okay Frank I myself am an avid 3D image
and hologram collector I have over 150
Holograms from non-sports cards as well
as others wow my question to you though
is regarding the meshika 3D camera this
is a camera that takes an image with
four lenses and creates a 3d effect of
the image not a stereogram only one
image is produced my problem is that
here in Canada there are no Developers
for the film The camera is similar to
the minslow 3D camera I'm wondering if
you know of any places that do develop
3D floor lens film if not thank you for
your time and trouble
I know this does not have anything to do
with holography this is 3D photography
using the Nim slow camera
but our 3D photographer friends are
actually brothers in arms and we both
enjoy three-dimensional Imaging to
techniques but close to the same result
sometimes so I thought I'd throw this in
here I'm not familiar with any
processing house right now that works
with the nymph slower than the sheikah
cameras that do 3D imaging
um
I know they have a number of throwaway
cameras now I think you pay 13 or 15
dollars for the camera
you take your pictures you send it in
that camera's been discarded and you get
your photos back so that seems to be the
way it's moving with this 3D photography
so
to be a buddy I'll send this out to the
audience if anyone knows where this
gentleman can get his film processed
would you please email me and let me
know the name and address of the photo
processing apps that can do this film
and I will forward it along to him so he
has a contact in the industry so he can
continue on with his Hobby and hopefully
maybe we can convince him to try
holography at some point which is a
wonderful three-dimensional Imaging
process so maybe we can help you out
okay we do have a news item this week I
find this news item very fascinating
tell us a little bit about it Deb okay
it's titled laser-powered projectile
flies 14 feet a laser-powered projectile
this is cool let's hear the news Okay
White Sand Missile Range New Mexico
scientists have successfully launched a
laser power test vehicle off the ground
using a technique that might someday be
used to put microsatellites into space
the advanced propulsion system operates
by shining the laser onto a parabolic
reflector located at the rear of the
light craft vehicle the reflector acts
as a concentrator for the laser beam air
is rapidly heated and forced out of the
nozzle at the back to propel the vehicle
in the spin stabilized free flight test
a pointing and tracking guidance system
actively locks the laser beam onto the
target
a more sophisticated guidance system
that includes steering capabilities is
scheduled for some time in the near
future
the long-term goal of the program is to
propel small microsatellites into orbit
such satellites would be about one half
to one meter in diameter with the mass
on the order of one kilogram
after being laser powered to the height
of forty thousand to one hundred
thousand feet the launching vehicle
would escape the remaining Atmosphere by
converting to laser heated rocket
propellant
well folks that about wraps it up for
another week
thank you for tuning in to hola talk
don't forget you can send in your
questions with our toll-free number
which is
1-800-458-3525 or send an email to
holotalk holoworld.com Ted thank you
very much for coming in you're welcome
and we'll see you next week take care
bye